<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rill's Blog</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/</link><description>Thoughts</description><atom:link href="https://rillonline.github.io/blog/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:@rillonline"&gt;Rill&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 20:09:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>My Writing is in Disarray</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/my-writing-is-in-disarray/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In some ways, the title says it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have started writing again and the question I asked myself is where I
wanted to put what I wrote. I have a love/hate relationship with my
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://rill.blog/"&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; blog. It is difficult to post there and I always want to
keep a copy locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My best bet is my &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/my-writing-is-in-disarray/rillonline.github.io/blog"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;, but it would not build under my new
installation of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://getnikola.com/"&gt;Nikola&lt;/a&gt;. It looks like I will have to edit every last
post (because struggling with the &lt;code class="docutils literal"&gt;conf.py&lt;/code&gt; is more than I can handle
at the moment.) Revisiting old posts is not a bad thing anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also started to revisit my Star Runner novels. I thought I would
collect them all in one place along with my blog posts. You see, there
is really method in my madness. Oh dear! I think there is one missing. I
can’t even think of its name. I was not super impressed with it, but it
did tell a story. I can probably recreate it if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several backup hard drives have crashed. Perhaps it was there. I have
also discovered I have many copies of the same file and everything needs
to be brought together in one place and cleaned up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m working in Linux on my ChromeBook which I really enjoy. I’m learning
a lot about Emacs, too, and that’s fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So as Babylon V says, "So it begins ..."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/my-writing-is-in-disarray/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 18:20:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>january-1</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/2020/01/holy-name/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I read this webpage today. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lectionarypage.net/YearABC_RCL/Christmas/HolyName_RCL.html"&gt;Holy
Name&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without a doubt, the hearer of these texts are to concentrate on the
name of Jesus and of all the ways we might engage God's name. But being
a more perverse person, that is not where my mind went. In
Philippians,Paul says "Let the same mind be in you that was in Christ
Jesus." (2:5). What does this mean? I have read these words many times
and have often wondered but never stopped to think about them
separately. Yes. Yes. Every knee should bow and all that, but what would
it mean to have the same mind as Jesus? The point is Jesus' servanthood,
Jesus' willingness to do God's will, to be God with us rather than God
apart from us. And so I begin the year thinking I might have a goal this
year to come back to these readings and be Christ to those I meet. It's
been a Christian practice forever, but I forget it all the time. People
get nervous around other people when they start spouting religion or say
things like, "Jesus loves you." I am not that sort of person. But I can
channel it and act as if I had said it. I want to be mindful of having
the mind of Jesus this year. Who knows. It might even become habitual.
And isn't that the point of resolutions anyway?)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/2020/01/holy-name/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>NanoWriMo Prep</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/2019/09/nanowrimo-prep/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.nanowrimo.org"&gt;Nanowrimo&lt;/a&gt; doesn't start until November 1, but an email dropped into my
inbox about Nanowrimo prep. I started reading over the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://preview.nanowrimo.org/nano-prep-101"&gt;material&lt;/a&gt; I began to sketch out my novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized I needed more information so I started reading Blake
Snyder's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/49464.Save_the_Cat"&gt;Save the Cat: The Last Book on Screenwriting You'll Ever Need&lt;/a&gt;. Yes, I know, it's about screenwriting but it is applicable to
novel writing, too. I also consulted Jessica Brody's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/32805475-save-the-cat-writes-a-novel"&gt;Save the Cat! Writes a Novel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized very quickly I did not have enough information to plot my
novel. I know the beginning and the ending, but I had no idea what
happens in the middle. And the middle is 60% of the novel. The ending
is clear, but not how the middle ends and how the ending begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead I realized I needed to go back to a project I started putting
together in 2015. I call this novel the Three Laws of Magic. I am
focusing on only one law of magic here: With great power comes great
responsibility. This will be familiar to those of you who use &lt;code class="docutils literal"&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt;
on your Linux machines. I am still not sure if the other admonishments
work here or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The novel I have set aside is clearly the third book in the series and
perhaps my experiments with &lt;em&gt;The Wizard of Marling&lt;/em&gt; is the second
book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's how I know &lt;em&gt;Mulberry Bend&lt;/em&gt; is the third novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Brody's book, she lists ten universal lessons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Forgiveness: of self or of others&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Love: includes self-love, family love, romantic love&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Acceptance: of self, of circumstances, of reality&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Faith: in oneself, in others, in the world, in God&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fear: overcoming it, conquering it, finding courage&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trust: in oneself, in others, in the unknown&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Survival: including the will to live&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Selflessness: including sacrifice, altruism, heroism, and overcoming greed&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Responsibility: including duty, standing up for a cause, accepting one’s destiny&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Redemption: including atonement, accepting blame, remorse, and salvation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know &lt;em&gt;Mulberry Bend&lt;/em&gt; is acceptance. I tried putting this with &lt;em&gt;The
Three Laws of Magic&lt;/em&gt; and I realized my protagonist doesn't accept who
she is at the end. So I looked through the list and came to the
conclusion that her growth point is responsibility. This is not as
great a leap for Ronnie Camberwell as acceptance will be. As I said, I
have no idea what book two will require.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having spent time with the 15 "beats" of &lt;em&gt;Save the Cat&lt;/em&gt;, I decided
this structure didn't fit my novel as well as my original structure as
laid out by Christopher Bogler in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/173302.The_Writer_s_Journey"&gt;The Writer's Journey: Mythic Structure for Writers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these books are based on Joseph Campbell's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/588138.The_Hero_With_a_Thousand_Faces"&gt;The Hero With a Thousand Faces&lt;/a&gt; which he published in 1949. Campbell posits that all stories from
all around the world have the same structure regardless of their
genre. As listeners, readers or watchers of story, we find this
structure satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've never been a plotter, but since I have had trouble writing this
novel in a general sort of way, I decided to try structure this time.
Stay tuned. There will be more as I proceed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/2019/09/nanowrimo-prep/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Story Idea for NanoWriMo</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/2019/09/writing-idea-for-nanowrimo/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://preview.nanowrimo.org/"&gt;Nanowrimo&lt;/a&gt; Prep email arrived in my inbox last week or maybe
earlier. I opened it up to find I have access to an entire workbook
and a weekly schedule to get ready. I've been going through the
document. Sadly many of the links were eight broken or not even inside
the pdf. Nevertheless, there's enough there to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't been able to write the story of Ronnie Camberwell arriving
in the Magic Lands and how she got stuck there. Perhaps it is one of
those stories that can eluded to but never written. I remember
that Rumpole had such a story.. Eventually John Mortimer wrote it and
it was so disappointing. It worked so much better when Rumpole
referenced it but kept the details foggy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working under this idea, I have decided to write a different story
while Ronnie is confined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's my outline so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="initial-idea"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Initial Idea&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The novel is called Mulberry Bend, A Ronnie Camberwell Novel&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It takes place after The Three Laws of Magic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It takes place in the capital city of the Magic Lands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To the uninitiated, the city appears to be a medieval city. To Ronnie,
it is a city with very extremes of well-being.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a very poor area called Five Points, there is a winding street
called Mulberry Bend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The mystery centers in this area and on this street.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-read-a-prompt-recently-about-a-lost-girl"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I read a prompt recently about a lost girl.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lost girl ends up in this section of the city. (This is based on
the 19th century area of New York City.) Tripp and Ronnie set out to find her. Explores the relationship between Tripp and Ronnie and is Ronnie's first trip outside of the wizard compound. Ronnie is restricted to the city. Tripp is still sexually attracted to Ronnie. Ronnie is conflicted, wanting Tripp but also tied to the absent Captain Star Runner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="some-ideas-about-the-lost-girl"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some ideas about the lost girl:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;a Tigerfu&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not from the capital city&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Grand Mistress Luna is very anxious that the girl be found so the
wizards reputation does not suffer but she is not invested in the
girl at all. Ronnie is appalled. Tripp is philosophical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The leader of the field trip is anxious that her reputation will
suffer if the lost girl is not found, but she is not really
invested in the girl either. Ronnie presses her to
understand. The girl is mute and her guardian merely wants the
girl off her hands. It seems everyone has this attitude. With
four hands, Ronnie can't figure out why the girl cannot sign and
make herself understood.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tripp explains the Tigerfu in this part of the Confederacy is not
particularly sympathetic to disabilities. It's a very frontier
mentality and everyone has to pull their own weight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ronnie has to rethink her idea about the Tigerfu and their
openness. Why doesn't this girl get any help. Can her disability
be mitigated? The Tigerfu are very advanced with surgery and
psychology. Can the girl speak and chooses not to because of
trauma or is she physically unable to speak?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ronnie checks the library catalog. Muteness is covered in the
catalog. From the entry, Ronnie believes the ancient wizards knew
something about it but she has not delved deeply enough into
reading the library volumes on these subjects to be fluent enough
to read the texts easily.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-rest-of-the-story"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Rest of the Story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I have the opening of the story but not what Tripp and Ronnie find
in Five Points. I don't know what becomes of the lost girl. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="where-is-ronnie-in-her-life-when-all-is-said-and-done"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where is Ronnie in Her Life When All is Said and Done&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know how Ronnie grows in this story and how her relationship
with the Tribunal of Wizards is changed. I've had a sense for some
time that Ronnie will eventually become the Grand Mistress and will
choose to stay, providing leadership for this collections of worlds
within the Tigerfu Confederacy. Her travel ban will be lifted so that
future adventures may occur elsewhere. But that is in the future and will not be realized in this novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/2019/09/writing-idea-for-nanowrimo/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Writing a Book: Part 1</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/2019/09/writing-a-book-part-1/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have started to write a book which gathers together some of my
previous posts on Org and then fleshes out the material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="setting-up-a-to-do"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Setting Up a To-do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first set up a to-do to track my progress. I am modifying the steps
as I go, but here is what it currently looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code text"&gt;&lt;a id="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-1" name="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;* STARTED Write a series of articles on getting organized with org mode [5/10]
&lt;a id="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-2" name="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-2"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a id="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-3" name="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-3"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;     1. [X] Gather all files into a new git repository
&lt;a id="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-4" name="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-4"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;     2. [X] Create a landing page for the ebook
&lt;a id="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-5" name="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-5"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;     3. [X] Write an outline for my getting organized articles
&lt;a id="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-6" name="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-6"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;     4. [X] Integrate blog posts into this outline
&lt;a id="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-7" name="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-7"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;     5. [X] Write a script to convert .org files to .md files and copy
&lt;a id="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-8" name="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-8"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;        them to the book directory
&lt;a id="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-9" name="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-9"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;     6. [ ] Write the book. Chapter by Chapter goes below.
&lt;a id="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-10" name="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-10"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;     7. [ ] Publish the ebook
&lt;a id="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-11" name="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-11"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;     8. [ ] Upload the ebook to archive.org
&lt;a id="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-12" name="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-12"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;     9. [ ] Update the download link on the landing page.
&lt;a id="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-13" name="rest_code_1bb6cec13c4a42369560bfb2330fc3d9-13"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;     10. [ ] Write a blog post announcing the book.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have checked off have of the items, but it is the easy stuff I've
checked off. So far I only have listed one items for writing the book
though I plan on adding check boxes underneath this item so I can
check off each chapter. The final check box is to review the entire
book and make any necessary corrections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"STARTED" is a to-do state that I developed for my projects. More on
that when I discuss "TODO" in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="setting-things-up"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Setting Things Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Setting up the git repository was very straight forward on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.
Then I looked over my blog and copied the posts that applied into
that directory and updated the repository.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I then wrote a landing page for the book. The idea of a landing page
is to have the potential reader focus on your book and the &lt;strong&gt;Call to
Action&lt;/strong&gt; which is for you, the reader, to click on the "buy" button.
My page is quite simple and does not have a "Download" button yet
since the book is not finished. You can look at it &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://rillonline.github.io/living-my-life-in-plain-text-page.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="outlining"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Outlining&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then set about putting together an outline to help me think about
what the book should cover. This is not set in stone. More chapters
may appear and the ones listed here may disappear. This is what it
currently looks like in Org markup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- code

** Table of Contents
** Introduction - - what this book hopes to accomplish
** Thinking About Doing
** A Few Quick Notes on Orgmode Markup
** Setting up your Initial Emacs Configuration for Org
** Setting up a Calendar
** Seeing Your Calendar as an Agenda
** Making a To-do List
** How Deep Should You Go?
*** To-do Checkboxes
*** To-do Keywords
*** Priorities
** Revisiting the Agenda
*** Helpful keys in the Agenda - - archiving, saving, changing status
*** Seeing the Agenda on STartup
*** Remember to Refresh
** Capturing Information
*** Deciding what to Capture
** To Refile or Not to Refile
** Writing in Orgmode
** Exporting and Publishing in Orgmode
** Keeping Track of Expenses
** References --&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="promotion-and-demotion"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Promotion and Demotion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In looking this over, the first thing I want to do is change the
headline level. I need to move everything up one level so that heading
3s become heading2s and heading2s become heading1s
What I want to do is called promotion. I highlighted the text, went to
the org menu and found "promote" under the "edit structure" menu item.
There is a shortcut key you can use if you do this often enough to
remember it "m-s-left". You can also demote items "m-s-right"..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="changing-headlines-into-lists"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changing Headlines into Lists&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can change headlines into lists and lists into headlines. I
changed my outline headings into an unordered list of to-do items by
highlighting them and then applying the command "c-c -". That's "c-c
hyphen". The "-" (hyphen) gives you the clue. The asterisks "*" are
replaced wit a hyphen "-". You can go the other way by using "c-c *" (asterisk).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="making-an-epub"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Making an Epub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-didn-t-work-for-me"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What Didn't Work for Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I investigated how to make an epub. Pandoc can do this. One of
the examples I found showed how to put a bunch of markdown files in a
directory and then turn them into an ebook. Great, I thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to use org-publish to do this but I could not get a batch
transformation of all org files. I've tried this in the past and the
markdown export function still hangs. I think I had 30 buffers open wantiiting
for something. I have no idea what&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found this script on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pandoc.org/faqs.html"&gt;pandoc site&lt;/a&gt; and modified it for my purpose:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- code

#!/bin/bash
# Convert all org files in a directory to markdown
# This script is to convert and move markdown into the book folder

for f in *.org;
do pandoc "$f" -s -o "${f%.org}.md";
done
mv *.md book/ --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I discovered I would have to include every filename in the
directory in my pandoc command. That seemed more trouble than it was
worth as the moment so I will just write in one file and perhaps split
it out at the end so that I can update it more easily. We'll see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-did-work-for-me"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What Did work for Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to add some YML stuff to the beginning of my file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- code

- - -
title: Living My Life in Plain Text
author: Rill Woolnough
rights: Creative Commons Attribution Non-commercial ShareAlike
- - - --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the pandoc command I am using:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- code

pandoc -o book.epub book.org - -toc - -toc-depth=3 --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="reading-the-epub"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reading the Epub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how to read it? Enter emacspeak. It uses the eww browser to render
the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- code

m-x     emacspeak-epub-open  ret
enter the path to the book ret --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Firefox is my default browser, the book opens there. There is
single letter navigation to move around in the book as if you are in a
regular web page. alt-f4 closes the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="back-to-work"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Back to Work!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I'm going back to writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/2019/09/writing-a-book-part-1/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>org-sort-list</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/2019/09/org-sort-list/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After sorting my lines using &lt;code class="docutils literal"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;m-x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="pre"&gt;sort-lines&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;, I have discovered org
itself has a sorting lines function. Here's how to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Highlight the list you want to sort.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code class="docutils literal"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;c-c&lt;/span&gt; ^&lt;/code&gt; (carat or s=6).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You will be prompted to indicate what kind of a sort you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;a for alphabetical&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;f for function which I will not cover&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;n for numeric&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;x for checkboxes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If these letters are capitalized, reverse order is used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/2019/09/org-sort-list/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>I Miss Her</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/2019/09/I-miss-her/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I must have written this in the fall of 2006. Caitlin, my first
Seeing Eye dog, died on July 10, 2006. Elwood did not come into my
life until November 27th. I always remember Caitlin, my chocolate
Lab, on her birthday, September 6, 1992. Thinking about her still
brings tears to my eyes and a lump in my throat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-miss-her"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I miss her&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;In the daily tasks,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;in the ordinary doing of things,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;I miss her.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;25minutes to an appointment–&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;I will take her out. There is time for that.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;And then, I miss her.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;I will sit in my chair. She will come to be petted, to ask for a biscuit.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;And then, I miss her.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;I lay down in bed at night and listen for her breathing by the foot of the bed.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;And then, I miss her.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;I awake in the morning and check the time. I will dress and take her out.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;And then, I miss her.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Her water bowl is no longer on the floor under the dishwasher door when I load and unload.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;And then, I miss her.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/2019/09/I-miss-her/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Turning Off Autofill-mode in a Single Buffer</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/2019/09/turning-off-autofill-mode-in-a-single-buffer/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my article on
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/09/02/using-checkboxes/"&gt;Using Checkboxes&lt;/a&gt; I discussed sorting lines in my ideas file. I went ahead
and added more ideas to the file. Because I sometimes forget details,
I decided to include many details in several entries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details are good, right? Well, not if they wrap to another line. This
messes up sorting since the sort doesn't know how to keep the
additional lines with their starting line. I knew that, but hoped
(unreasonably) that everything would stay together. Of course, it
didn't. So I had to look for a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is simple enough. Auto-fill-mode is turned on by default.
In general, auto-fill-mode is a good thing. When the line gets too
long, Emacs inserts a line break and a new line is started. Happily,
when typing in org-mode as I was, Org appropriately wraps the line with a
two space indentation. Org knows my additional words belong to this
list item. HTML will know it, too, because Org will tell it by
enclosing the whole thing in "&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;" tags. But sort-lines is
emphatic that a line is a line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution, not surprisingly, is to turn off auto-fill-mode in this
buffer. But how? I started searching for the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The readily available answer was this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="system-message"&gt;
&lt;p class="system-message-title"&gt;System Message: ERROR/3 (&lt;span class="docutils literal"&gt;&amp;lt;string&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;, line 26)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cannot find pygments lexer for language "example"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;.. code:: example

   m-x auto-fill-mode
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This toggles auto-fill-mode on and off. If it is on to begin with, all
I have to do is toggle it off when I open the file and life is good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except … well, except that I want to write ideas with long
explanations because I forget. And it is &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; likely I will forget
to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allthough it took some time, I finally found a way to do this so
auto-fill-mode would be turned off for the buffer and I don't have to
remember what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I placed the following line at the top of my ideas file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="system-message"&gt;
&lt;p class="system-message-title"&gt;System Message: ERROR/3 (&lt;span class="docutils literal"&gt;&amp;lt;string&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;, line 43)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cannot find pygments lexer for language "example"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;.. code:: example

   ;; -*- mode: org; mode: auto-fill -1; -*-
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I refresh the current buffer via the Org menu and autofilling stopped.
&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: I did find I had to use "-1" rather than "0" to turn off
auto-fill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edited 2019-09-07. I originally had the mode as text when it should be org.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/2019/09/turning-off-autofill-mode-in-a-single-buffer/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Walk in the Park with Nick</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/2019/09/a-walk-in-the-park-with-Nick/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nick and I walked to catch a direct bus home from my salon
appointment. It was a nice day and catching the bus near the salon
would have required several complicated street crossings and a bus transfer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had trouble connecting with my GPS. In the end, I think I hadn't
turned on my remote for my hearing aids. As a result, I was not fully
engaged with exactly where we were. Nick was so excited to go down new
streets. He became impatient with all my stopping and fiddling with technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turning Nick around is always challenging. He seems to think that this
will make the walk end too soon even when we have walked for some
time./~/org/using-fly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally we got onto a street that ran alongside the park. I was happy
because it meant we only had one big street crossing to go before the
bus stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick took the opportunity to turn into the park. We had walked through
there once before, but I did not have a good grasp on the macadam
paths. I thought I had turned Nick around to go back onto the
sidewalk, but he had other ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found myself going up hill and down at a great rate of speed. Happy
dog. GPS is basically useless in a park. At one point we came near to
some identifiable streets, but they were on the east side of the park.
I needed to be on the west side of the park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked some more. I didn't think we were in any danger, but I did
wonder if Nick would ever consent to leave the park. I started
thinking about who I could call to come and find us. I had no good
options. I finally decided Nick would eventually get hungry and tired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At last we exited the park. Unfortunately, Nick was going in the
opposite direction that I wanted to go. He was opposed to changing
direction. Eventually I prevailed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked alongside the park. We had often done this when we lived in
the high rise. Nick thinks of this route as a going home route so he
was less than enthusiastic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we got to the bus stop, Nick began to whine. The only thing worse
than walking home is not walking at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be curious to know how we do the next time we walk home from
the salon. Will a detour into the park be de rigueur.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/2019/09/a-walk-in-the-park-with-Nick/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Using Checkboxes</title><link>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/2019/09/using-checkboxes/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wrote about
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://rillonline.github.io/posts/2019/08/28/recurring-tasks-in-orgmode/"&gt;Recurring Tasks in Orgmode&lt;/a&gt; previously. Once I had this to-do working properly,
I went onto the next task. I wanted to list my ideas for articles and
bigger writing projects. In my opinion, I did not need to set this all
up as a big list of to-dos. That certainly becomes overwhelming to
me.I might just stop writing altogether because the ideas keep coming
but the time and patience to write them may not be available at the
moment. I do
want to be sure I have a stash of ideas to choose from when I am able
to sit down and write out a complete article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created a file name "ideas.org". I inserted three headings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="system-message"&gt;
&lt;p class="system-message-title"&gt;System Message: ERROR/3 (&lt;span class="docutils literal"&gt;&amp;lt;string&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;, line 14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cannot find pygments lexer for language "example"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;.. code:: example

   * Writing Ideas Big and Small
   ** Blog Ideas [/]
   ** Bigger WRiting Projects [/]
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that at the end of the second level headings
there are two square brackets "[]" enclosing a slash "/". More on this
later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="organizing-the-list"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organizing the list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I thought I would just write a list like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="system-message"&gt;
&lt;p class="system-message-title"&gt;System Message: ERROR/3 (&lt;span class="docutils literal"&gt;&amp;lt;string&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;, line 29)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cannot find pygments lexer for language "example"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;.. code:: example

   - smart quotess and other typography
   - less than shortcuts in orgmode
   - Braile pack at public museum
   - photo op with Nick
   - a walk in the park with Nick
   - using org capture
   - Using checkboxes in org
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I thought about using checkboxes so I could check them off as I
went. Now this section of the file looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="system-message"&gt;
&lt;p class="system-message-title"&gt;System Message: ERROR/3 (&lt;span class="docutils literal"&gt;&amp;lt;string&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;, line 42)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cannot find pygments lexer for language "example"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;.. code:: example

   - [ ] smart quotess and other typography
   - [ ] less than shortcuts in orgmode
   - [ ] Braile pack at public museum
   - [ ] photo op with Nick
   - [ ] a walk in the park with Nick
   - [ ] using org capture
   - [ ] Using checkboxes in org
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who knows, you might even see some of these articles in the future!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="why-use-checkboxes"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why Use Checkboxes?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why use checkboxes? After all, I could simply delete the item from the
file once I published it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a good point. I decided to try this methodology just to see how I
liked it and for two other reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It would let me know how I was doing at keeping up with my ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It would let me know if I needed to be thinking more about writing
opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that a writer is stuck here: Coming up with ideas and
getting them written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="using-the-checkboxes"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Using the Checkboxes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To check off an item, press "c-c c-c" on that line. Then you have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:- [X] Using checkboxes in org&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what the heading now looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="system-message"&gt;
&lt;p class="system-message-title"&gt;System Message: ERROR/3 (&lt;span class="docutils literal"&gt;&amp;lt;string&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;, line 79)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cannot find pygments lexer for language "example"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;.. code:: example

    ** Blog Ideas [1/7]
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I turn the "/" (slash) into a percent sign (%) it looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:&lt;a href="https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/2019/09/using-checkboxes/#id1"&gt;&lt;span class="problematic" id="id2"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;* Blog Ideas [14%]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="system-message" id="id1"&gt;
&lt;p class="system-message-title"&gt;System Message: WARNING/2 (&lt;span class="docutils literal"&gt;&amp;lt;string&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;, line 85); &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/2019/09/using-checkboxes/#id2"&gt;backlink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline emphasis start-string without end-string.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I feel ambitious, I can delete these lines or I can sort them so
that all the unchecked boxes are together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sorting-lines"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sorting Lines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Highlight the list&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Type "m-x sort-lines". All the checked off items will be gathered
together at the end of the list. The items appear in alphabetical
order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="system-message"&gt;
&lt;p class="system-message-title"&gt;System Message: ERROR/3 (&lt;span class="docutils literal"&gt;&amp;lt;string&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;, line 98)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cannot find pygments lexer for language "example"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;.. code:: example

   - [ ] Braile pack at public museum
   - [ ] a walk in the park with Nick
   - [ ] less than shortcuts in orgmode
   - [ ] photo op with Nick
   - [ ] smart quotess and other typography
      - [ ] using org capture
   - [X] Using checkboxes in org
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list now is in a different order than the way I originally
wrote it down. I can read through it until I come to an item with a
checkbox. I know there are no more new items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I want to sort in reverse order, I type: "c-u m-x sort-lines".
Here is what I now have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="system-message"&gt;
&lt;p class="system-message-title"&gt;System Message: ERROR/3 (&lt;span class="docutils literal"&gt;&amp;lt;string&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;, line 115)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cannot find pygments lexer for language "example"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;.. code:: example

   - [X] Using checkboxes in org
   - [ ] using org capture
   - [ ] smart quotess and other typography
   - [ ] photo op with Nick
   - [ ] less than shortcuts in orgmode
   - [ ] a walk in the park with Nick
   - [ ] Braile pack at public museum
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't think I will use this ordering unless I need a confidence
boost. I would have to go past everything I've already done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/2019/09/using-checkboxes/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>