<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>rillonline.github.io/blog/</id>
  <title>What Happened Today?</title>
  <updated>2021-08-13T14:24:22.785742+00:00</updated>
  <link href="rillonline.github.io/blog/"/>
  <link href="rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://ablog.readthedocs.org/" version="0.10.19">ABlog</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/my-writing-is-in-disarray/</id>
    <title>My Writing is in Disarray</title>
    <updated>2021-08-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="my-writing-is-in-disarray"&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some ways, the title says it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have started writing again and the question I asked myself is where I
wanted to put what I wrote. I have a love/hate relationship with my
&lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;WordPress&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;_ blog. It is difficult to post there and I always want to
keep a copy locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My best bet is my &lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;em&gt;, but it would not build under my new
installation of &lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;Nikola&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. It looks like I will have to edit every last
post (because struggling with the &lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;conf.py&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; is more than I can handle
at the moment.) Revisiting old posts is not a bad thing anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also started to revisit my Star Runner novels. I thought I would
collect them all in one place along with my blog posts. You see, there
is really method in my madness. Oh dear! I think there is one missing. I
can’t even think of its name. I was not super impressed with it, but it
did tell a story. I can probably recreate it if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several backup hard drives have crashed. Perhaps it was there. I have
also discovered I have many copies of the same file and everything needs
to be brought together in one place and cleaned up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m working in Linux on my ChromeBook which I really enjoy. I’m learning
a lot about Emacs, too, and that’s fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So as Babylon V says, “So it begins …”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.. _WordPress: https://rill.blog/
.. _github: rillonline.github.io/blog
.. _Nikola: https://getnikola.com/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    <link href="rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/my-writing-is-in-disarray/" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In some ways, the title says it all.</summary>
    <published>2021-08-02T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/great-day/</id>
    <title>Great Day</title>
    <updated>2021-08-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="great-day"&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is a great day for Nick and me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, we have been together for five years now. Our
anniversary was a few days ago, but I’m writing about it now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick and I had a rocky start, but we have been loyal to one another
through it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is an especially wonderful day because we finally got out on a
walk together. For the past two weeks or so I have struggled with
unhealthy air quality and high levels of grass pollen. Today air
quality was in the good range and the pollen counts were low for grass,
tree and ragweed. So off we went for our usual daily walk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had no difficulty breathing and could keep up with Nick’s pace which
was neither slow nor fast. Nick behaved well, at least for Nick on a
walk, and that was great, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    <link href="rillonline.github.io/blog/posts/great-day/" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Today is a great day for Nick and me.</summary>
    <published>2021-08-10T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
